<?xml version="1.0" standalone='no'?>
<!DOCTYPE manpage SYSTEM "http://masqmail.cx/xmltoman/xmltoman.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://masqmail.cx/xmltoman/xmltoman.xsl" ?>

<manpage name="update-grml-rescueboot" section="8" desc="Script to integrate Grml ISO for booting via GRUB">

<synopsis>
  <cmd>update-grml-rescueboot [-f] [-t <arg>small|full</arg>]</cmd>
</synopsis>

<description>
  <p>
    grml-rescueboot integrates Grml ISO booting into GRUB.
    It provides a script for update-grub which looks for Grml ISO images in <file>/boot/grml</file>,
    and automatically adds an entry for each image.
    The purpose is to use one of those images to boot a Grml rescue system without using a CD, USB stick or network boot (PXE).
  </p>

  <p>
    <file>update-grml-rescueboot</file> is a script which checks for the latest stable version of Grml (via download.grml.org),
    ensures there is enough free disk space in <file>/boot/grml</file> and downloads the ISO to <file>/boot/grml</file>.
    It verifies the ISO signature and upon success executes update-grub then.
    Everything should be ready for booting a Grml ISO via GRUB then.
  </p>

  <p>
    This script makes it even easier to integrate a Grml ISO into GRUB via grml-rescueboot.
    All that needs to be done is to install grml-rescueboot and then invoke update-grml-rescueboot.
    Using the <arg>-t</arg> option, it is possible to use specific Grml ISOs.
    If this option is not specified, it defaults to the <arg>full</arg> flavour
    matching the hardware architecture (amd64 or arm64).
  </p>
</description>

<options>

<option>
  <p><opt>-f</opt></p>
  <optdesc>
    <p>
      Force execution, ignoring, e.g. existing ISO files and disk space checks for <file>/boot/grml</file>.
    </p>
  </optdesc>
</option>

<option>
  <p><opt>-h</opt></p>
  <optdesc>
    <p>
      Display usage information and exit script.
    </p>
  </optdesc>
</option>

<option>
  <p><opt>-t <arg>arg</arg></opt></p>
  <optdesc>
    <p>
      Choose Grml flavour, specified via <arg>arg</arg>.
      Supported flavours are 'small' and 'full'.
      If unset defaults to 'full'.
    </p>
  </optdesc>
</option>

</options>

<section name = "Author">
  <p>
    update-grml-rescueboot was written by Michael Prokop, based on a script by Felipe Sateler.
  </p>
</section>

<section name = "Bugs">
  <p>
    Please report them towards Debian's BTS, see https://bugs.debian.org/grml-rescueboot.
  </p>
</section>

</manpage>
